Guide to the Jewish Labor Committee Records, Part I WAG.025.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Administrative and Organizational Records
  - Subseries I:C: Correspondence
    - Sub Subseries 1C3: Correspondence: With Other Organizations (arranged alphabetically)
      - Unions: ILGWU: Joint Board Cloak...Makers, 1941-1942 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Unions: ILGWU: Joint Board Cloak...Makers, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Unions: ILGWU: Joint Board Cloak...Makers, 1944-1947 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Unions: ILGWU: Joint Board Dress & Waistmakers, 1934-1940 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Unions: ILGWU: Joint Board Dress & (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Waistmakers, 1941-1942 (Box 12, Folder data_value_missing_d66c3555be111af3e26483ea7184ee02)
      - Unions: ILGWU: Joint Board Dress & Waistmakers, 1943-1944 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Unions: ILGWU: Joint Board Dress & Waistmakers, 1945-1947 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Unions: ILGWU, Local 155, 1943-1944 (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Unions: ILGWU, Local 155, 1945-1947 (Box 12, Folder 16)
        Reel#: 28
      - Unions: ILGWU: Locals, 1934-1939 (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Unions: ILGWU: Locals, 1940-1942 (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Unions: ILGWU: Locals, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - Unions: ILGWU: Locals, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - Unions: ILGWU: Locals, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 21)
      - Unions: ILGWU: Locals, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 22)
      - Unions: ILGWU: Locals, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 23)
      - Unions: International Ladies Handbag, Pocketbook, & Novelty Workers (ILHPNW), 1935-1939 (Box 12, Folder 24)
      - Unions: ILHPNW, Locals, 1942-1947 (Box 12, Folder 25)
      - Unions: United Hatters, Cap and Millinery Workers International Union (UHCMW), 1935-1936 (Box 12, Folder 26)
      - Unions: UHCMW, 1941-1945 (Box 12, Folder 27)
      - Unions: UHCMW, 1946-1947 (Box 12, Folder 28)
      - Unions: United Retail, Wholesale and Chain Store Food Employees Union, 1942-1946 (Box 12, Folder 29)
      - Unitarian Service Committee, 1942-1944 (Box 12, Folder 30)
      - United China Relief, 1943-1944 (Box 12, Folder 31)
      - United Export Clothing Co., 1942-1946 (Box 12, Folder 32)
      - United Hebrew Trades, 1934-1947 (Box 12, Folder 33)
      - United Jewish Appeal, 1939-1945 (Box 12, Folder 34)
        Reel#: 29
      - United Workers Educational Organizations, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 35)
      - Vaad Hahatzalah, 1942-1945 (Box 12, Folder 36)
      - Volunteer Christian Committee to Boycott Nazi Germany, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 37)
      - Volunteers of America, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 38)
      - J. A. Want Organization, Inc, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 39)
      - War Assets Administration, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 40)
      - War Chest, NY State: Proposal, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 41)
      - Workers' Defense League, 1938-1947 (Box 12, Folder 42)
      - World Jewish Congress, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 43)
      - World Jewish Congress, 1941-1943 (Box 12, Folder 44)
      - World Jewish Congress, 1944-1947 (Box 12, Folder 45)
      - World Union of Labor Zionist Parties, 1943-1944 (Box 12, Folder 46)
      - Yiddish Writers Union, 1941-1947 (Box 12, Folder 47)
      - Zloczower Relief Verband of American, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - Subseries I:D: Meetings, Conferences and Other Events (arranged chronologically)
    - Conference, Jun 25, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Vladeck Testimonial Dinner, Oct 1934 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Conference against Fascism, Dec 1934 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Emergency Conference: American Jewish Congress, Jul 1935 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Vladeck-Locker Debate, Dec 1935 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - World Labor Athletic Carnival [The original program for this event, which was originally part of the materials in this folder, has been removed and stored in the Tamiment Library's vault.], 1936-1937 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - World Labor Athletic Carnival (Box Shared Tamiment 044, Folder 1)
    - Vladeck Luncheon, Oct 1, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Conference, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Roumanian Labor League, Jan 24, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      Reel#: 30
    - Conference: Situation in Germany (I), 1938 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Conference: Situation in Germany (II), 1938 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Vladeck Memorial Meeting (I), 1938 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Vladeck Memorial Meeting (II), 1938 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Vladeck Memorial Meeting, Nov 3, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Special Plenary Session, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Conference, Aug 1939 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Conference, Nov 9, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Protest Meeting against Nazi Terror, Dec 13, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Roumanian Labor League, May 22, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Roumanian Labor League, Jun 30, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Workmen's Circle Conference, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Meeting: Plenum, Oct 10, 1941 (Box 13, Folder 22)
      Reel#: 31
    - General Jewish Council: Seminar, Oct 19, 1941 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Conference, Nov 16, 1941 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Meeting with D. Ben-Gurion, Apr 1942 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - American Slav Congress, Apr 25, 1942-Apr 26, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Meeting with C. Weitzmann and D. Ben-Gurion, May 1942 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Mass Meeting, Jul 21, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Memorial Meeting for Cherniakov, Aug 26, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Meeting with President Roosevelt, Dec 8, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Roumanian Labor League, Dec 20, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Erlich and Alter Memorial Meeting, Mar 30, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Memorial Meeting for the Heroes of the Warsaw Ghetto, Jun 19, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - American Jewish Conference, Aug 29, 1943-Sep 2, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Conference: "Americans Talk It Over", Nov 23, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Scherer Farewell Meeting, Sep 8, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      Reel#: 32
    - Vladeck Memorial Meeting, Nov 7, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Vladeck Memorial Meeting: Delegates, Nov 7, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Seminar on Current Jewish, Nov 19, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Roumanian Labor League, Jan 23, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Chernov Testimonial Dinner, Mar 26, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Commemoration of the Anniversary of the Warsaw Ghetto Uprising, Apr 19, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Women's Rally, May 21, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Demonstration against the Slaughter of European Jews, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Roumanian Labor League, Dec 3, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Roumanian Labor League, Jan 21, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - "Heroes and Martyrs of the Ghettos" (Exhibit): Replies to Invitations, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - "Heroes and Martyrs of the Ghettos": Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - "Heroes and Martyrs of the Ghettos": Publicity, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - "Heroes and Martyrs of the Ghettos": Opening, Apr 19, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Luncheon, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - American Labor Conference on International Affairs, Jan 12, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Dinner, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Dinner, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Leon Blum Luncheon, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Paris Peace Conference, Jun 1946 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Meeting, Oct 10, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Molly Picon and Jacob Kalich Banquet, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 23)
      Reel#: 33
    - World Conference on Jewish Culture: Planning Session, Feb 18, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 23A)
    - Anti-Defamation League: Conference, Oct 23, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Luncheon, Nov 12, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Leon Blum Dinner, Dec 4, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Subseries I:E: General Files (arranged alphabetically by subject)
    - Adler, Friedrich, 1941-1947 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Anti-Fascist Activity, 1934-1935 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Anti-Fascist Activity, 1936-1937 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Anti-Fascist Slogan Project, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Anti-Nazi Boycott, 1933-1934 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Anti-Nazi Boycott, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Anti-Nazi Boycott, Women's Conference, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Anti-Nazi Leaflets, 1934-1938 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Anti-Nazi Periodicals, 1941-1943 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Anti-Semitism, 1944-1947 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Anti-Semitism in the United States, undated, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Anti-Semitism in the United States, 1940-1944 (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Architect: Schlanger, Ben, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Aufbau: Correspondence, 1943-1946 (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Austrians in America, 1945-1946 (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Bermuda Conference, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - Book Fund, 1945-1947 (Box 14, Folder 43)
      Reel#: 34
    - Budgets, 1938-1947 (Box 14, Folder 44)
    - Campaign against U.S. Govt. Transactions with Nazi Germany, 1934-1936 (Box 14, Folder 45)
    - Clippings: United Nations, 1943-1944 (Box 14, Folder 46)
    - Clippings: USA (I), 1943 (Box 14, Folder 47)
    - Clippings: USA (II), 1943 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Clippings: USA (III), 1944 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Communist Anti-Nazi Activity, 1934-1935 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Communist-Influenced Activity, 1939-1943 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - "Communists and the JLC," ms. & notes by Pinchos Schwartz, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Contributions, 1941-1942 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Contributions, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Contributions, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Contributions, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Reel#: 35
    - Contributions, Jan 1947-Sep 1947 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Contributions, Oct 1947-Dec 1947 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Dan, Theodore: Research Project, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Day (Der Tog): Correspondence, 1934-1947 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Facts and Opinions: Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Foreign-Language Press, Aug 1, 1946-Jul 1, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Semi-Monthly Survey of the Leading Foreign Language Press, Sep 1, 1947-Sep 15, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Semi-Monthly Survey of the Leading Foreign Language Press, Sep 16, 1947-Sep 30, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Semi-Monthly Survey of the Leading Foreign Language Press, Oct 1, 1947-Oct 15, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Semi-Monthly Survey of the Leading Foreign Language Press, Oct 16, 1947-Oct 31, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Semi-Monthly Survey of the Leading Foreign Language Press, Nov 1, 1947-Nov 15, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Semi-Monthly Survey of the Leading Foreign Language Press, Nov 16, 1947-Nov 30, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Semi-Monthly Survey of the Leading Foreign Language Press, Dec 1, 1947-Dec 15, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Semi-Monthly Survey of the Leading Foreign Language Press, Dec 15, 1947-Dec 31, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Free Ports, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Free Voice of Labor: Correspondence, 1944-1947 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Fundraising, 1934-1936 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Fundraising, 1937-1939 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Fundraising, 1940-1945 (Box 15, Folder 28)
      Reel#: 36
    - Fundraising, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - German-Americans, 1934-1943 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - German-Americans, 1944-1945 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Germany: Social Democrats, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Haller, Isaac: Visit to USA, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Hungarian-Americans, 1941-1944 (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Immigration Matters, 1943-1945 (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Immigration Matters, 1946-1947 (Box 15, Folder 35A)
    - International Day of Mourning, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Jewish Anti-Defamation Work in Pre-Hitler Germany, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Jewish Central Information Service: Holocaust Survivors' Reports, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - Jewish Culture Conference, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - Jewish Daily Bulletin, 1934-1935 (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - Jewish Daily Bulletin, 1934-1947 (Box 15, Folder 41)
      Reel#: 37
    - Jewish Telegraphic Agency, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Jewish Telegraphic Agency, 1943-1944 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Jewish Telegraphic Agency, 1945-1946 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Jewish Telegraphic Agency, Feb 1947-Jun 1947 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Jewish Telegraphic Agency, Jul 1947 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Jewish Telegraphic Agency, Aug 1947 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Jewish Telegraphic Agency, Sep 1947 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Jewish Telegraphic Agency, Oct 1947 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Jewish Telegraphic Agency, Nov 1947 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Jewish Telegraphic Agency, Dec 1947 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      Reel#: 38
    - Jewish World News Service, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Justice: Yiddish-language ILGWU newspaper, 1934 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Labor and Nation: Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Labor Chest, 1934 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Labor Chest, Jan 1935-Mar 1935 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Labor Chest, Apr 1935-May 1935 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Labor Chest, Jun 1935-Jul 1935 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Labor Chest, Aug 1935-Dec 1935 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Labor Chest, 1936-1937 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Labor Day Greetings, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Latvian Americans, 1943-1945 (Box 16, Folder 20A)
    - Letters of Introduction and Reference, 1944-1947 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Lists of European Socialist and Trade Union Leaders, 1941-1944 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Lists of Names and Addresses, undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Meetings, 1943-1947 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Morning Journal: Correspondence, 1934-1937, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Nation: Correspondence, 1943-1946 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - National Resources Planning Board, 1942-1943 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Nazi-Occupied Europe: Resistance, 1941-1944 (Box 16, Folder 28)
      Reel#: 39
    - Neue Volkszeitung: Correspondence, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - New Leader: Correspondence, 1934-1947 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - New Republic: Correspondence, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - New York Labor War Chest, A.F. of L., 1943-1945 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Office of Strategic Services, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Office of War Information, 1942-1945 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Oswego Refugee Shelter, 1944 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Oswego Refugee Shelter, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Oswego Refugee Shelter, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - Overseas News Agency, Inc., 1942 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - Petition to President Roosevelt, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Reel#: 40
    - Picon, Molly and Jacob Kalich, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Poland: Anti-Semitism, 1937, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Poland: Campaign against Pogroms, 1934-1935 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Poland: Campaign against Pogroms, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Polish Americans, 1941-1946 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Polish Consulate, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Polish Consulate, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Polish Consulate, 1944-1945 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Polish Embassy, 1942-1945 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Polish Press Agency, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Press: Public Relations, 1934-1935 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Press: Public Relations, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Press: Public Relations, 1944-1947 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Press Releases: English, 1942-1943 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Press Releases: English, 1944-1945 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      Reel#: 41
    - Press Releases: English, 1946-1947 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Press Releases: Yiddish, Jan 1942-May 1942 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Press Releases: Yiddish, Jul 1942-Dec 1942 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Press Releases: Yiddish, Jan 1943-Apr 1943 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Press Releases: Yiddish, May 1943-Aug 1943 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Press Releases: Yiddish, Sep 1943-Dec 1943 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Press Releases: Yiddish, Jan 1943-May 1944 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Press Releases: Yiddish, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Press Releases: Yiddish, 1946, undated (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Press Releases: Yiddish, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Press Releases: Yiddish, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 27)
      Reel#: 42
    - Quoddy Project, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Racial Discrimination, 1942-1943 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Rent Control, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Report on Discrimination against Jews in Employment (ILGWU), 1936 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Research Dept.: Abramowitz, R., undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Research Dept.: American Jewish Conference, 1943 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Research Dept.: American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee, 1942-1945 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Research Dept.: Anti-Nazi Movement in Europe, 1940-1942 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Research Dept.: Arab/Jewish Relations, 1940 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Research Dept.: B'nai B'rith, The Facts, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Research Dept.: B'nai B'rith, The Facts, Jan 1947-Jun 1947 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Research Dept.: B'nai B'rith, The Facts, Jul 1947-Dec 1947 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Research Dept.: Canada, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Research Dept.: Commission for National Problems, 1941-1942 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Research Dept.: Conference on Jewish Demography, 1945-1946 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Research Dept.: Conference on Jewish Postwar Problems, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Research Dept.: Correspondence, 1941 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Research Dept.: Correspondence, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Research Dept.: Correspondence, 1943 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Research Dept.: Correspondence, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Research Dept.: Correspondence, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Research Dept.: Correspondence, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Research Dept.: Correspondence, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Research Dept.: Econ. Commission, 1941-1943 (Box 18, Folder 24)
      Reel#: 43
    - Research Dept.: France, 1940-1944 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Research Dept.: France, 1945-1946 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Research Dept.: Human Rights, undated, 1942-1947 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Research Dept.: Institute of Jewish Affairs, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Research Dept.: Juridic Commission, 1941-1942 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Research Dept.: Leib Jubilee Committee, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Research Dept.: Minutes, Reports, and Resolutions, 1941-1943 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Research Dept.: National Conference on the German Problem, Mar 1947 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Research Dept.: Norway, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Research Dept.: Poland, 1944, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Research Dept.: Poland, Pre-war Jewish Population, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Research Dept.: Postwar Peace Demands for the Jews, 1941-1946 (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Research Dept.: Publication Research, 1944-1945 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Research Dept.: Research Material, 1943-1944 (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - Research Dept.: Research Material, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - Research Dept.: Research Material, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - Research Dept.: Russia, undated (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - Research Dept.: United Nations Economic and Social Council, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - Research Dept.: United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Admin. (UNRRA), 1942 (Box 18, Folder 43)
    - Research Dept.: Vishniak, Mark, 1942-1947 (Box 18, Folder 44)
      Reel#: 44
    - Rublee Program for Emigration of German Jews, 1939 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Russian Americans, 1941-1947 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Social Security, etc. (JLC staff), 1948 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Soviet Embassy, 1941-1942 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Special Labor Aid Project (SLAP): Account Books, 1943-1944, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - SLAP: Agendas and Minutes, 1943-1947 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - SLAP: Amalgamated Bank of NY, 1944-1946 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - SLAP: Bonds, 1943-1946 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - SLAP: Card Files, undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - SLAP: Contributions, 1943-1946 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - SLAP: Correspondence, 1943 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - SLAP: Correspondence, 1944 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - SLAP: Correspondence, 1945-1947 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - SLAP: Cuba: Octave Biquard, 1944-1946 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - SLAP: Cuba: Correspondence, 1944-1946 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - SLAP: Cuba: Recipients, 1944-1946 (Box 19, Folder 16)
      Reel#: 45
    - SLAP: Cuba: Arthur Wolff, 1944-1946 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - SLAP: Financial Statements, 1943-1946 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - SLAP: Licenses, 1943-1944 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - SLAP: Physicians, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - SLAP: Applications, 1943-1946 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - SLAP: Recipients: General, 1943-1944 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - SLAP: Recipients A-I, undated (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - SLAP: Recipients J-S, undated (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - SLAP: Recipients T-Z, undated (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Staff: Office Employees Int'l Union, Local 153, 1946-1947 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Stalin-Hitler Pact: JLC Statement, 1939 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Subversive Organizations: Lists, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Szygelboym, Arthur (Szmul): in the U.S., 1940-1941 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Ukrainian Americans, 1941-1946 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - United Service Organizations, 1942-1945 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - United States Congress, 1942-1947 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - U.S. Congress: JLC Immigration Poll, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 32A)
      Reel#: 46
    - U.S. Coordinator of Information, 1942 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - U.S. Dept. of Commerce, 1946-1947 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - U.S. Dept. of Justice, 1945-1947 (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, 1945-1947 (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - U.S. Dept. of State, 1935-1938 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - U.S. Dept. of State, 1941-1945 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - U.S. Dept. of State, 1946-1947 (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - U.S. Internal Revenue Dept., 1941, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - U.S. Presidents, 1942-1946 (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - U.S. Student Assembly, 1944-1945 (Box 19, Folder 42)
    - U.S. Treasury Dept., 1944 (Box 19, Folder 43)
    - U.S. War Dept., 1944-1945 (Box 19, Folder 44)
    - Vladeck Memorial Fund, 1938-1939 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Vladeck Memorials, 1939-1940 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Voice of the Unconquered: Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Voice of the Unconquered: Correspondence, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Voice of the Unconquered: Correspondence, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      Reel#: 47
    - Voice of the Unconquered: Correspondence, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - War Production Board, 1943-1945 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - War Refugee Board, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - War Relief Control Board, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - WEVD: Radio Station, 1943, 1946-1947 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Yiddish Encyclopedia Committee, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Yiddish Encyclopedia Committee, 1941-1947 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Yiddish Scientific Institute (YIVO), 1939-1941 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - YIVO, 1942-1943 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - YIVO, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - YIVO, 1945-1946 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - YIVO, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Zionism and Palestine: Debates and Proposals, 1942 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Zionism and Palestine: Misc., 1940-1947 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Zionism: Protests, 1939-1940 (Box 20, Folder 20)
      Reel#: 48
    - Zukunft, 1943-1945 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Zukunft, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Zukunft, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Subseries I:F: Scrapbooks, 1936-1947 [Note: These scrapbooks were in extremely fragile condition and were destroyed after filming.]
    - Labor Athletic Carnival (Counter Olympics), 1936
      Reel#: 49
    - Clippings, 1937
    - Labor Athletic Carnival, 1937
    - Clippings, 1938
      Reel#: 50
    - Clippings, 1939
    - Clippings, Feb 1936-Mar 1937
      Reel#: 51
    - Clippings, Jan 1940-Sep 1941
    - Clippings, Jan 1944-Jun 1944
      Reel#: 52
    - Clippings, Jul 1944-Dec 1944
    - Clippings, Jan 1945-May 1945